Are you looking to use returns data,
to improve your e-commerce business?
Well, if you want to learn more,
stick around.
Did you know
your returns data
is a goldmine of insightful information
just waiting to be uncovered?
Using an automated returns management system
allows e-commerce retailers like you
to easily track their returns
and gradually create a pool of data.
That data can be leveraged to provide insight
into product quality,
customer expectations,
and weaknesses in the business operational process.
Method 1: Improve Your Product Descriptions
Accurate product descriptions
build trust with customers.
They help e-commerce shoppers make informed buying decisions
without even physically seeing the product.
Returns data
can be used to improve product descriptions
to accurately illustrate each item
so customers know what they’re purchasing.
Method 2: Improve the UX Website Design
The same insight gathered from returns data
can also be used to improve the overall experience
of the company website.
Providing an image or chart
of how the product is expected to fit
will boost the shopping experience for customers
by limiting confusion.
This also improves brand perception
by making the customer feel like the retailer
goes the extra mile.
Method 3: Improve Your Business Operations Process
The goal of any business
is to provide the best experience
for their customers.
A seamless internal process ensures that.
Analyzing metrics like average fulfillment time
can be used to pinpoint and fix problems
with staffing, resources,
operating times, etc.
to ensure all customers are
getting their orders on time.
Method 4: Learn More About Your Customers
Providing the best experience to your customers
is always going to be a top priority.
When an e-commerce merchant
knows nothing about their customers,
this task becomes close to impossible.
That’s where returns data comes into play.
Analyzing customer returns behavior
using the RFM (recency, frequency, monetary) Model,
merchants can segment customers
into key clusters
and form a more personalized marketing strategy,
which will ultimately increase the customer lifetime value.
Method 5: Reduce Your Retail Return Rates
The final and most obvious way returns data
can be used to make profitable business decisions
is by reducing return rates.
You should want your products to stay in the hands of your customers.
While everything mentioned above
will help to reduce return rates,
our giant pool of returns data
from retailers across industries
lets us make discoveries
that would be hard to uncover
if you were just looking at the returns data
from your company.
We’ve uncovered some valuable insight
on reducing return rates:
Offering warranties as a return type
reduces the refund rate by 10%.
Returns are becoming more popular
as more and more people shop online.
But those returns aren’t a detrimental part
of e-commerce business.
Customer returns behavior
can be analyzed to identify which parts of the business
can be improved to reduce return rates
and increase the loyalty of customers.
To see an example
of an actual e-commerce company
that was able to improve their business practices
based on returns data,
check out our case study on Ecru,
a women’s fashion brand that
was able to cut their multi-size purchases by 15%.
Thank you for watching today's video.
If you haven't already,
feel free to hit the like button down below.
And hit the subscribe button,
which is located on the right corner of the screen.
If you want to learn more about this content,
make sure to check out the blog
and the case study
which I have linked in the description below.
And i'll see you guys on the next video.